{
    "composers": {
      "Frédéric Chopin": {
        "quizzes": [
          {
            "question": "Fryderyk Chopin is best known for his compositions for which instrument?",
            "options": ["Violin", "Piano", "Flute", "Guitar"],
            "answer": "B"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which musical form did Chopin transform, infusing it with emotional depth and technical precision?",
            "options": ["Sonata", "Symphony", "Concerto", "Étude"],
            "answer": "D"
          },
          {
            "question": "What nationality was Fryderyk Chopin?",
            "options": ["French", "German", "Polish", "Austrian"],
            "answer": "C"
          },
          {
            "question": "Chopin's 'Minute Waltz' is known for its:",
            "options": ["Slowness and tranquility", "Length and complexity", "Lively tempo and brevity", "Dark mood and intensity"],
            "answer": "C"
          }
        ]
      },

      "Robert Schumann": {
        "quizzes": [
          {
            "question": "Which of these pieces is a composition by Robert Schumann?",
            "options": ["The Magic Flute", "Für Elise", "Dichterliebe", "The Barber of Seville"],
            "answer": "C"
          },
          {
            "question": "Schumann’s music is often noted for its:",
            "options": ["Classical formality", "Dance-like rhythms", "Emotional depth", "Religious themes"],
            "answer": "C"
          },
          {
            "question": "Robert Schumann was a leading composer of which musical era?",
            "options": ["Baroque", "Classical", "Romantic", "Modern"],
            "answer": "C"
          },
          {
            "question": "Schumann’s ‘Scenes from Childhood’ is written for which instrument?",
            "options": ["Violin", "Piano", "Flute", "Cello"],
            "answer": "B"
          },
          {
            "question": "Who was a significant influence in Schumann's life and music?",
            "options": ["Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "Johann Sebastian Bach", "Clara Wieck", "Felix Mendelssohn"],
            "answer": "C"
          }
        ]
      }
      
    },
    "instruments": {
      "Piano": {
        "quizzes": [
          {
            "question": "Which composer is known for their innovative compositions for the solo piano?",
            "options": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "Frédéric Chopin", "Ludwig van Beethoven"],
            "answer": "C"
          },
          {
            "question": "The piano is classified as which type of musical instrument?",
            "options": ["String", "Percussion", "Woodwind", "Brass"],
            "answer": "B"
          }
        ]
      }
    },
    "compared": {
      "Beethoven's Symphony No.5 and Mozart's Symphony No.40": {
        "quizzes": [
          {
            "question": "Which symphony is known for its 'fate motif' of three short notes followed by one long note?",
            "options": ["Beethoven's Symphony No.5", "Mozart's Symphony No.40", "Beethoven's Symphony No.9", "Mozart's Requiem"],
            "answer": "A"
          },
          {
            "question": "Mozart's Symphony No.40 is in which key?",
            "options": ["C Major", "G Minor", "D Minor", "B Flat Major"],
            "answer": "B"
          }
        ]
      },
      "Tchaikovsky's Swan Lake and Bach's Brandenburg Concertos": {
        "quizzes": [
          {
            "question": "Which work is a famous ballet?",
            "options": ["Tchaikovsky's Swan Lake", "Bach's Brandenburg Concertos", "Beethoven's Fidelio", "Mozart's The Magic Flute"],
            "answer": "A"
          },
          {
            "question": "How many Brandenburg Concertos did Bach compose?",
            "options": ["3", "6", "9", "12"],
            "answer": "B"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  }
  